Régis Calmejane

IT Support Technician



32rue de Dudelange 57330 Volmerange les Mines France



+33 650 80 96 95



regcal@gmail.com

IT Support Skills

• • • • • Windows 7 / 8 / 10

Mac OS X+

Outlook

Office Suite

Active Directory

• • • • O Hardware

SCCM

OOO Mobile Iron

OOOO Windows server

IT Support Activities

- VIP / proximity support
- Ticketing systems
- Troubleshooting & escalation
- Hardware maintenance
- Hard/software deployment

IMAC



French: Native speaker
English: Good level of
conversational English and IT
technical vocabulary



Find out more on www.linkedin.com/in/regis-calmejane

I am hard working, reliable and a team player. I quickly integrate a new environment and learn new processes and systems. I am always willing to help others. I enjoy training and coaching and I have good people skills.

After a first IT-related position obtained with my self-taught IT skills and knowledge, I undertook an adult education course to have the necessary qualifications to continue on my career path.

Over the years, I have supported a wide range of software and operating systems in French and English, over the phone, on site and via email/live chat. I have learned to use various systems for ticket management, quality control and customer satisfaction. I have some ITIL awareness in incident, problem and change management. My various experiences with different ticketing systems allow me to understand and adapt quickly.



*07/09/2018-07/09/2019: Parental leave

Luxembourg

2019 - now IT Technical support at European Investment Bank for Intrasoft Netcompany Intl

2017 – 2019* Technical Service Desk Agent αt European Court of Auditors for Aubay

2015 – 2016 Hardware Field Engineer at Hewlett Packard for Trasys (13 months)

2014 – 2015 IT Technical support at European Investment Bank for GFI (13 months)

2014 Technical support agent at European Court of Justice for Aubay (7 months)

rance (Meuse)

2013 Various IT Technician temp missions (6 months)

2012 Front office user support agent for Certi (6 months mission)

2011 Support agent level 1 at RBC Dexia for Halian (3 months mission Lux) Ireland (Dublin)

2008 – 2011 Technical Support Agent for Hewlett Packard Microsoft (8 months)
General Electric (18 months)
Société Générale (6 months)
Total France (9 months)

France (Toulouse)

2007 Hotline Support Agent at Orange, Tiscali, La Poste for Bugbusters (3 months mission)

2007 Intern at INSA Toulouse for Arctia (3 month internship)

2005 IT Engineer at Alcatel space for Hewlett Packard (3 months mission)



Education

2006 – 2007 Junior Windows and Linux Network Administrator - Toulouse (France) (Adult education course, equivalent of a 2-year university-level degree)

1995-1997: B.T.S Force de vente - Toulouse (France) (2 years university-level course in sales techniques)

1994 – 1995 Baccalauréat STT (Science and Tertiary Technology) - Figeac (France)



Since November 2019:

IT Technical Support Agent at European Investment Bank for Intrasoft -Netcompany Intl

Incident Tracking via Smart Reporting SPOC (single point of contact) for users Windows 10 / office 2016 User help

Remote control /Software installation via SCCM (PAM)

Problems diagnosis and resolution (Hardware, software and network). Vpn (teleworking: token, smartcard, Windows Hello) support Handling / managing tickets queue and mail queue.

On site support resolution of Work order and incidents sent by Service Desk.

Techpoint assistance user aims to put a human face to the IT Service Desk, offering personalized IT Support effort to provide top quality services.

Onboarding new users.

Inventory (managing 5 people)

IMAC IT equiments installation, moves and return updating the CMDB accordingly

Technologies Windows 10 and 11, Office 2016, Office 365, SCCM

Ticketing system: BMC Helix Smart IT Remote control: SCCM

January 2017- November 2019

Technical Service Desk Agent at European Court of Auditors for Aubay

Incident / request / change Tracking via SDM, ITIL process

SPOC (single point of contact) for users /VIP support

Installation / reimaging of PC and devices, software installation

Issue diagnosis and resolution (Hardware, software and network).

Onsite support

VPN (teleworking token) support

Mobile support (Android/iOS) Mobile Iron

Windows 10 Migration: In charge of the Windows deployment for laptops,

hard disk encryption check (Sophos Safeguard), stock management, CMDB update and in charge of the coordination between helpdesk and deployment team.

November 2015 – December 2016

Hardware Field Engineer at Solutions30 / Hewlett Packard for Trasys

Hardware break-fix interventions cases in Luxemburg and Belgium on HP hardware: desktop PCs, laptops, tablets and printers. Troubleshooting issues (UEFI and HP tools) and changing the affected parts on site at the customer's premises Logistics for all the parts (Pick up / Drop off)

Technologies

Windows 7 and 10, ZCM, Office 2010-2016, Outlook 2013-2016, SCCM, LDAP, Sophos Safeguard, Mobile iron

Ticketing system: SDM Remote control: Zenwork and SCCM

Technologies

Windows 7 and 10, HP tools (diagnostics, troubleshooting, etc.) Ticketing system: Solutions30

September 2014 - October 2015

IT Technical Support Agent at European Investment Bank for GFI

Incident (diagnosis/resolution) & request tracking via SDM SPOC (single point of contact) for users / VIP support Installing / reimaging PC and other devices, software installation via SCCM VPN (teleworking, token and Smartcard) support and GSM support Front office and proximity support IT stock management (IMAC)

Technologies

Windows 7, Office 2010-2013 Ticketing system: BMC Remedy Remote control tool: SCCM

itinuea) Public

January - August 2014

Technical support agent at European Court of Justice for Aubay

Front office Technical agent:

Answering all customer IT issues / requests (Tickets creation, record and follow-up)

Incident diagnosis and resolution (Hardware, software and network), escalation of incidents if necessary

France - 2011 to 2013

March – September 2013

IT technician (Several temp missions)

Windows 7 Deployment: formatting, data transfer, installing, deployment & onsite support

Printer, PC and Axel terminal installation base, IT support on site

June – December 2012

Front office user support agent (6-months contract) at Certi (Nancy)

Troubleshooting, analysing and escalating issue with procedure solution for URSSAF users Escalate calls to the right group

Solve issue based on knowledge or procedures

October - December 2011

Support agent level 1 at RBC Dexia (Luxembourg) for Halian (Telindus)

Troubleshooting bank issue with Operational Procedure Solution. Escalate calls to the right group

Solve issue based on procedures

Dublin, Ireland - 2008 to 2011 January 2008 - August 2011

Universal Support Agent at Microsoft (January – August 2011)

Microsoft CLOUD computing BPOS/ Office365:

- Provided advance troubleshooting for the Cloud Computing technology offered by Microsoft Online Service
- Provided IT Support in both French and English for small/large companies in EMEA.
- Focused on root cause analysis, prevention, and knowledge transfer.
- Developed a relationship with both the customer and technical peers.

Technical support agent level 2 at General Electric (June 2009 – Dec. 2010)

- Resolving remote user incidents (first time fix without escalation if possible)
- Managing the desk ticket queue and SLA

Technical Support Agent Level 2 *at* **Société Générale Asset Management** (Dec. 2008 – May 2009)

First stage: knowledge transfer from existing desk in Paris to Dublin (2-month mission in Paris)

- Identifying resolution groups, ticket escalation criteria and process
- Listing all the applications used by the helpdesk
- Observing on-site processes
- Studying and updating new ticketing system
- VIP support

Second stage: coaching level one agents, and troubleshooting all issues that level one could not solve (Dublin)

- Set up tools and connections
- Train level one agents and provide support on a daily basis
- Update and maintain the knowledge base.

Technical Support Agent level 1 at Total France (February – October 2008)

- Answer calls as SPOC (focus on first call resolution), troubleshooting or escalation
- Create incident / request tickets
- Respect SLAs and quality expectations
- VIP support.

Technologies
Windows 7, Office 2010, Active
Directory
Ticketing tool: SDM
Remote control tool: SCCM

Technologies
Windows XP, Office 2010
Ticketing tool: Redmine
Remote control tool: Logmein

Windows / Osifice 2010, Sara, Bloomberg

Ticketing tool: Peregrine, Omnitracker

Technologies

OS: BlackBerry, Windows XP to 7, Windows Server 2008 r2

Software: Office 2000-2010, Exchange online, Sharepoint online, Live Meeting online, Communicator, Active Directory, Citrix,Safeboot PC encryption, Cognos, Lotus Notes, RSA token.

Ticketing tools: Operation Services Delivery, Rightnow, SolutionsDesk, ITSM, Remedy and BMC

Remote control tools:

Microsoft remote desktop, Teamviewer, 123rescue, Landesk, VNC, Netmeeting



Work experience details (continued)

Toulouse, France – 2005 to 2007

September - December 2007

Hotline Support Agent at Orange, Alice (Tiscali), La Poste for Bugbusters

- Deployment of the new computing network and upgrade from Windows 2000 to XP
- Using team knowledge and knowledge base to troubleshoot issues
- IT hotline helping users after physical installation by ISP

March - May 2007

Adult Training Internship at National Institute of Applied Science for Arctia

- Supervising the Linux network with free software RANCID and Cacti
- Making graphs to manage active network components
- Creation of a live map to detect issues and monitor usage on the network

May - July 2005

Computing Engineer (3 month contract) at Alcatel space for Hewlett Packard

- Deployment of the new hardware and upgrade from Windows 2000 to XP
- Formatting, installing, deployment and support for 3300 Hewlett Packard laptops
- Supporting users with issues on the new system.

Technologies

Windows XP, MS Office 2007 Ticketing tool: HPSD Remote control tools: Netmeeting, Pc Anywhere

Technologies

Windows XP, Office 2007, Linux script, RANCID and Cacti.

Technologies

Windows NT/2000 to XP, Office 2003, Blanco (HP formatting tool), Symantec ghost DVD for deployment.

June 1997 - May 2005

Non IT-related positions (Toulouse)



Hobbies and interests



Board games



Swimming



Movies / Culture



Video games



Gardening



Yoga



Walking / Nature



Cooking